# Felix Zhou

1B Computing and Financial Management 200 University Ave W, Waterloo, ON N2L 3G1 604-518-0141 | cfzhou@uwaterloo.ca

#### SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

- Outstanding Leadership Skills: demonstrated through a myriad of leadership positions
- Strong Problem-Solving Abilities: exemplified through diverse project profile and strong test scores
- Well-Versed Communication Capabilities: displayed through familiarity of 3 languages and experience communicating both informally with younger children and formally with management staff

#### HACKATHONS, PROJECTS, & COLLABORATIONS:

YHacks - AWS, Bash Scripting, CSS, JavaScript, Linux

2017

Cooperated with 3 hackers to create a Node JS emotion recognition application. Leveraged a Deep Neural Network for an emotional analysis of a sound file. The application also utilizes a speech-to-text-to-emotion API. Currently hosted via Elastic Computing on a virtual Linux machine.

Hack Princeton - Node JS, RESTful APIs, Microsoft Azure

2017

Collaborated with hackers around the continent to create an automated Sales and Trading Bot using the Microsoft Azure platform. Clients are provided up-to-date information on any stock symbol. Users can set minimums and maximums and determine when the bot should sell or purchase a stock.

Session Tracker - Python, Pyramid, SQLite, SQLAlchemy, ORM

2017

Employed the Pyramid framework for Python to build a web application which accesses a RESTful API and registers unique session IDs according to requests coming from the same browser. Utilized ORM to store session identifiers and information such as date, page, and time for each request made within a given session in a SQLite database.

Expenditure Tracker - Java, Servlets, MySQL, HTML

2016

Developed an application which allows users to access a MySQL server and track their spending. Java servlets and a JDBC driver are implemented as part of a basic MVC architecture. Login credentials are hashed and salted before being stored. A virtual machine running CentOS from AWS is the current server.

## SKILLS & TALENTS:

Languages

Native proficiency in Mandarin and English Professional working proficiency in French

Music

Grade 10 piano with First Class Honors with Distinction

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

Teaching Assistant | Kumon Education

2016-2017

Clarifies confusing topics for individual students from basic arithmetic to introductory Calculus Communicates with management team about scheduling availabilities in a professional manner

LEADERSHIP:

Associate | hEDGE Financial Conference

2017-present

Plans for guest speakers, workshops, mock interviews, case competitions, and networking sessions Develops and maintains the conference website, server, and database for applications and such Contacts potential sponsors for partnership opportunities

Team Captain | Varsity Basketball Team

2012-2017

Acts as medium between 12 players and 3 coaches to ensure instructions are understood Learned to make split-second decisions under pressure

# **EDUCATION:**

Moscrop Secondary

4433 Moscrop St, Burnaby, BC V5G 2G3

• Bilingual Dogwood Degree: June 2017

SAT I: 1540, SAT Physics: 790, SAT Math II: 800, AP Computer Science A: 5, AP Macroeconomics: 5, AP Statistics: 5, AP Physics 1: 5, AP Physics 2: 5, AP Calculus BC: 5, AP English Literature and Composition: 5, AP French: 5

University of Waterloo

200 University Ave W, Waterloo, ON N2L 3G1

• Candidate for Bachelor's Degree in Computing and Financial Management: June 2022 President's Scholarship, Mathematics Entrance Scholarship

Designing Functional Programs (advanced), Elementary Algorithm Design and Data Abstraction (advanced), Calculus I (advanced), Calculus II (advanced), Algebra (advanced), Linear Algebra I (advanced), Probability

#### **AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS:**

Advanced Placement International Diploma

2017

Moscrop Secondary Physics Student of the Year

2015-2016, 2016-2017

Winner of Tournament of Towns Mathematics Contest

2015

Future Business Leaders of America Regionals – 3<sup>rd</sup> Place Economics

2015